[Evans] There are many different ways we could solve this problem.
解决这个问题的方法有很多种
First we'll look at a way of solving it using a while loop.
首先 我们来看看使用 while 循环的解决方法
We'll define our find_element procedure.
我们将定义我们的 find_element 函数
We'll use p as the name of the list and t as the name of the target,
我们将用 p 作为列表的名字 用 t 作为目标的名字
the element that we want to match.
也就是我们想要匹配的元素
We'll define the loop to go through the elements of p,
我们将定义这个循环来遍历 p 中所有元素
similarly to the previous while loops we've seen that go through lists.
这跟我们之前见过的遍历列表的 while 循环相似
We have our while loop. We've introduced the variable i.
我们有一个 while 循环 我们已经引入了变量 i
We'll use that as the index to go through the loop.
我们将用它作为索引来遍历循环
The stopping condition for the while loop is when i reaches the len(p),
while 循环停止的条件是当 i 达到 len(p)
so we want our test for the while loop to be i < len(p).
所以我们要让 while 循环的判断为 i < len(p)
In the block of the while loop we want to check if the current element matches t,
这个 while 循环的程序块中 我们要检查当前元素与 t 匹配
so we get the current element using p[i] and then we use == to test if it's equal to t.
于是我们使用 p[i] 得到当前元素 接着用 == 来测试它是否等于 t
If we find a match, meaning the 2 values are equal,
如果我们找到一个匹配 即找到两个相等的值
then we want to return the index that we found.
那么我们就要返回找到的索引
So the result should be the value of i,
所以结果应为 i 的值
which is the index where we found the matching element.
这就是我们找到匹配元素的索引
The risky thing about using while loops instead of for-loops
相对于使用 for 循环 使用 while 循环的风险在于
is it's really easy to forget that you need to increase the index variable.
你很容易忘记你需要增加所以变量
If we just left the loop like this, it would run forever
如果我们把循环就这样放着 它会永无休止地运行
because the value of i would never change unless the first element matched,
因为如果找不到第一个匹配的元素 i 的值就永远不变
in which case we would return 0.
这样 我们就返回0
The loop would just keep going on forever, again checking the first element.
这个循环会不停继续下去 再次检查第一个元素
So we need to increase the value of i,
所以我们需要增加 i 的值
and that's the end of the while block.
这就是 while 循环块的结尾
The way we described what the find_element procedure should do,
我们这样描述 find_element 过程应做什么
if the element was not found, it should return -1.
如果找不到元素 过程应返回－1
If we get to the end of the while loop without returning,
如果我们完成了 while 循环而没有返回
that means we've gone through the while loop for all values of i up to len(p) - 1.
这意味着我们已经遍历了 while 循环所有 i 的值直至达到 len(p)-1
We didn't find any element that matches, so we should return -1.
我们没有找到任何匹配的元素 所以我们应返回 -1
So that's one way to define find_element.
这就是定义 find_element 过程的一种方法
I'll also show you a way to define it using a for-loop.
下面我将向你展示如何使用 for 循环来定义该过程
The reason it's more natural to start thinking of defining find_element with a while loop
我们开始思考定义 find_element 时会更自然地想到使用 while 循环
than a for-loop is because the value that we want to return from find_element
而不是 for 循环 是因为我们想从 find_element 返回的值
is the index itself.
是索引本身
When we use a for-loop with the standard syntax of going through the elements
当使用一个采用标准句法遍历循环中元素的 for 循环
of the loop, we don't keep track of the index.
我们不追踪索引
We just see each element in order.
我们看到的只有依次排列的各个元素
So we need to add something else to keep track of the index
所以我们需要添加一些内容来追踪索引
because that's the value we want to return.
因为索引是我们想要返回的值
So we still need to use a variable to keep track of the index.
所以我们仍然需要使用一个变量来追踪索引
We'll use i as that variable just like we did in the while loop version.
我们将使用 i 作为变量 正如之前在 while 循环中的做法
Now instead of a while loop we'll have a for-loop.
现在我们有一个 for 循环 而不是 while 循环
We don't need to think of the stopping condition here
在这里我们不需要考虑停止条件
because it will just go through all the elements.
因为它只会遍历所有元素
Similarly to the body of the while loop, we check if the current element is equal to t.
与 while 循环主体相似 我们检查当前元素是否等于 t
In the for-loop we can get the current element using the variable e.
在这个 for 循环中 我们可以通过使用变量 e 来得到当前元素
That's what gets assigned each time we go through the loop body
每次我们遍历循环主体时
to the value of the current element.
当前元素就是这样被赋值的
So our test is using == to compare e and t.
我们的判断是使用 == 来比较 e 和 t
If they match, just like we did in the while version, we should return the result.
正如我们之前的 while 循环的做法 如果它们匹配 我们应返回结果
The result we want to return is the index where we found the match.
我们想要返回的结果是我们找到匹配的索引
In the while version that was clear.
在之前的 while 循环中 这点已经明确了
It made sense because we were looking at element p, index i.
这很好理解 因为我们看的是元素 p 索引 i
In the version with the for-loop we have to be more careful to know where that index is.
在 for 循环中 我们必须更加注意 要知道那个索引在哪里
We're using the variable i to keep track of that index, so we'll return i.
我们使用变量 i 来追踪那个索引 所以我们将返回 i
i starts at 0.
i 从0开始
Each time through the loop we need to increase i
每一次遍历循环我们都需要增加 i
so we keep track of the current index as we go through the elements.
所以 我们在遍历元素时追踪当前索引
As with the previous definition, when we had the while loop,
正如在之前的定义中 我们使用 while 循环
if we got to the end without finding it, that meant that the element did not exist in p
如果到了结尾我们没有找到元素 那就意味着这个元素在 p 中不存在
and we should return -1.
我们应返回 - 1
We'll do the same thing here.
在这个 for 循环中 我们同样这么做